<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>PGP on Serden-Yilmaz Kose</title>
    <link>http://sykose.xyz/tags/pgp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PGP on Serden-Yilmaz Kose</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://sykose.xyz/tags/pgp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get started with PGP!</title>
      <link>http://sykose.xyz/pgp/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://sykose.xyz/pgp/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to PGP messaging</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-is-pgp">What is &ldquo;PGP&rdquo;?</h1>
<p>PGP stands for &ldquo;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy">Pretty Good Privacy</a>&rdquo;, and it is a program used to encrypt messages. It is free to use, and open-source (the code is public). It was written by Phil Zimmermann in the 1990s.</p>
<h1 id="what-do-you-mean-by-encrypted-message">What do you mean by &ldquo;encrypted message&rdquo;?</h1>
<p>An encrypted message means the message isn&rsquo;t read as clear text. It&rsquo;s the difference between this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-txt" data-lang="txt"><span style="display:flex;"><span>This is a sample.
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>This is a sample text file.  I created it with an editor.  If it were
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>an actual message, it would contain some useful information.
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>This has been a sample.
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>and this:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-pgp" data-lang="pgp">-----BEGIN PGP MESSAGE-----
Version: 2.6.2

hIwD1vwet/TdJfEBBACdcCPkNI3kRwYqtHUyfpvVAY5rt+Lb9P6EztNd4sYq9egV
CZjfqcCn36XZmYPbbO6nZbl992kPRFzTgCRszKNPtlk6Wa93AqXs3KCZp+4emXQh
7moE+XTf4QUGJZ2L3w/sSNs5WFkZRIbto0ivK1aRlX1XTqhPqo9HbgEfElBVUaYA
AACQEWaOS3/h6BVLHTfXaK20vmLcg9BUisB5RDvYGLZv9XFwHMMjctFJJQYnWIOp
+7LLkmNO5fE48rWh0EOAwjAeduGzJGQb4yiE7OlxoESmmTJQ+qO1K2nDz8Stk3a6
WvAQJrpEUY7Og8QGlQQRPKl2F++j6XbIhZ27OeYqJp+vgylUd874KDMCcTrzF3ph
/Qfi
=xTV9
-----END PGP MESSAGE-----
</code></pre><p>*Example provided by <a href="https://people.cs.rutgers.edu/~watrous/pgp-eat.html">Rutgers&rsquo; University&rsquo;s Computer Science Department</a>.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s much harder to make any sense out of the encrypted text, right? Well, that&rsquo;s the point!</p>
<h1 id="but-gmail-and-whatsapp-tell-me-their-website-and-my-messages-are-encrypted">But GMail and WhatsApp tell me their website and my messages are encrypted!</h1>
<p>Sure, the website is encrypted, and so are your message (to some extent). But the idea behind using PGP, or some equivalent, isn&rsquo;t to complicate matters by adding more layers of encryption; PGP is a great tool to mask your messages in the case of a leak. Websites are hacked into, and their data is dumped online, all the time. What good would a chatlog be if it was filled with encrypted text? Very little. If the messages were in plain text, then it would be worth a lot (at the cost of your privacy). Moreover, PGP offers a lot more than mere message encryption, but we&rsquo;ll get into that later.</p>
<h1 id="why-should-i-even-care">Why should I even care?</h1>
<p>Read <a href="/pgp/why_pgp">this article</a> on the subject.</p>
<h1 id="wherehow-do-i-start">Where/how do I start?</h1>
<h2 id="how-does-it-work">How does it work?</h2>
<p>In order to use PGP, you need to know a little bit about how it actually works. Here is the run-down:</p>
<ul>
<li>Everyone has a <strong>public</strong> and <strong>private</strong> key. These are essentially how you are identified as the person you claim to be. This prevents me from imitating you, and sending messages on your behalf. The <strong>public</strong> key is to be shared with everyone, but the <strong>private</strong> key should never leave your computer (hence the name). Here is <a href="/syk.asc">my public key</a>, download it.</li>
<li>To send me an encrypted message, you must write the message (in clear text), then encrypt it using my <strong>public</strong> key. That message can only be decrypted using my private key. The technology behind this is mind-boggling and fascinating, but you don&rsquo;t need to understand it.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="is-there-an-app-i-can-use">Is there an app I can use?</h2>
<p>There are dozens of PGP graphical software apps out there, but only one is known for it&rsquo;s ease of use; I personally find <a href="https://www.openpgp.org/software/kleopatra/">Kleopatra</a> to be the standard when it comes to PGP messaging. Install it to follow the rest of this guide.<br>
<strong>NOTE</strong>: Kleopatra is available on Windows, but you should ideally use Linux for an optimal experience.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-encrypt-messages-using-kleopatra">How to encrypt messages using Kleopatra?</h2>
<p>Here are all the steps needed to start using Kleopatra:</p>
<ul>
<li>Click on <strong>File</strong>, then click on <strong>New OpenPGP Key Pair</strong>.</li>
<li>Add your name and/or Email address (the information does not have to be authentic).</li>
<li>Optional: Password protect your key (I highly recommend this).</li>
<li>Choose the Key Material. Go with the default if you don&rsquo;t know the differences in key material.</li>
<li>Optional: Choose expiration date of the key.</li>
<li>If you chose to password protect your key, type in your password in the field. Type it again to verify.</li>
<li>Click OK, and voila! Your key has been created.</li>
<li>Right click on your key from the main menu, and click on &ldquo;Export&rdquo;. Save the <strong>public</strong> key to a .asc file, and share it around!</li>
<li>To encrypt a message, go to &ldquo;Notepad&rdquo; on the taskbar. Type in your message.</li>
<li>Select the recipient&rsquo;s public key under &ldquo;Encrypt for others&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Click on &ldquo;Encrypt Notepad&rdquo;, and there is your encrypted message!</li>
</ul>
<p>Great! You now have a safely encrypted message. Send it to the recipient using the platform of your choice (E-Mail may be preferred).</p>
<h2 id="how-to-decrypt-messages-using-kleopatra">How to decrypt messages using Kleopatra?</h2>
<p>Here are the steps to decrypt a PGP message using Kleopatra:</p>
<ul>
<li>Paste the encrypted message into your notepad.</li>
<li>Click on &ldquo;Decrypt/Verify Notepad&rdquo;</li>
<li>If your private key is password-protected, type in the password when prompted.</li>
<li>The decrypted message should now appear in the notepad.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="what-else-can-i-do-with-pgp">What else can I do with PGP?</h1>
<p>Something you can do using PGP technology is digitally signing your messages. A PGP-signed message will look like this:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-pgp" data-lang="pgp">-----BEGIN PGP SIGNED MESSAGE-----
Hash: SHA512

Hello, this message is digitally signed.
Everyone can both read the content.
You can verify I am the true author of this message.
-----BEGIN PGP SIGNATURE-----

iHUEARYKAB0WIQR657wQ2YpjkKxAywZa2EuFS5oaQQUCaEO/WQAKCRBa2EuFS5oa
QSV5AQCgixyVnTNgdReMdu6GFGZ/2aj5YVGOafTfMM15FZtPtQD/bKdxnB+0ZTes
zEyLJEB2wRnoNEkG0Cd9xqbGIGTdkQM=
=E81E
-----END PGP SIGNATURE-----
</code></pre><p>The message goes under <code>BEGIN PGP SIGNED MESSAGE</code>, and the actual digital signature goes under <code>BEGIN PGP SIGNATURE</code>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
