<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Serden-Yilmaz Kose</title>
    <link>http://sykose.xyz/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Serden-Yilmaz Kose</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:56:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://sykose.xyz/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bring back the meaning of words!</title>
      <link>http://sykose.xyz/blog/stop_saying_genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:56:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://sykose.xyz/blog/stop_saying_genius/</guid>
      <description>If you can solve a soduku puzzle, you are a genius!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-beginning">The Beginning</h1>
<p>Have you noticed that people constantly, and wrongly,overuse <strong>very</strong> powerful words? Word like genius, obsession, addiction, trauma, etc&hellip;? Why do people do this?</p>
<h1 id="the-problem">The Problem</h1>
<p>When you overuse these words, you slowly alter the true meaning of the word. And I understand that languages change overtime, for various reasons, but why should we delibaretly devlue a powerful word like &ldquo;genius&rdquo;? If half a population is labeled as &ldquo;genius&rdquo;, then there is no &ldquo;genius&rdquo;. A genius in a field comes a few times every generation. If someone is somewhat profficient in some field, it doesn&rsquo;t make them a genius! Instead, it makes them somewhat profficient in that field. Everything is relative.</p>
<h1 id="the-solution">The Solution</h1>
<p>&hellip; isn&rsquo;t easy. Simple, maybe, but not easy. Be more careful with your vocabulary. Next time you want to use a superlative, think it through; does the subject merit the superlative of said adjective? Probably not. Next time you want to say you &ldquo;hate&rdquo; something, reconsider that feeling. A linguistically enhancing, and potentially spiritually enhancing, would be to not use the word &ldquo;hate&rdquo; for a week. You can replace that word with &ldquo;dislike&rdquo;, &ldquo;avoid&rdquo;, &ldquo;prefer not&rdquo;, &ldquo;refrain&rdquo;, etc&hellip; Find creative ways to rebuild your speech, you won&rsquo;t regret it!</p>
<h1 id="a-picture-of-an-actual-genius">A Picture Of An Actual Genius</h1>
<p><img alt="Nikola Tesla, with his equipment" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e9/Nikola_Tesla%2C_with_his_equipment_EDIT.jpg">
Image: <em>Dickenson V. Alley</em>, <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Nikola_Tesla,_with_his_equipment_EDIT.jpg">Nikola Tesla, with his equipment</a>, Wikimedia Commons, public domain.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
